{
    "flashcards": [
        {
            "question": "What is the process of converting high-level language code into machine-readable instructions?",
            "correct_answer": "Compilation",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Interpreting",
                "Lexis",
                "Syntax"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which term refers to the vocabulary of a programming language?",
            "correct_answer": "Lexis",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Semantics",
                "Interpreting",
                "Compilation"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the structure or rules that define the valid combinations of symbols in a programming language?",
            "correct_answer": "Syntax",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Semantics",
                "Interpreting",
                "Compilation"
            ],
        },Ã¥
        {
            "question": "Which of the following are valid Python keywords?",
            "correct_answer": "Keywords",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Indentation",
                "Instructions",
                "Comments"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which element in Python is used to indicate the beginning and end of a block of code?",
            "correct_answer": "Indentation",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Keywords",
                "Instructions",
                "Comments"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which element in Python is used to provide additional explanations or annotations within the code?",
            "correct_answer": "Comments",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Keywords",
                "Instructions",
                "Indentation"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which type of literals represent true or false values in Python?",
            "correct_answer": "Boolean",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Integers",
                "Floating-point numbers",
                "Scientific notation",
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which type of literals represent whole numbers in Python?",
            "correct_answer": "Integers",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Boolean",
                "Floating-point numbers",
                "Scientific notation",
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which type of literals represent decimal numbers in Python?",
            "correct_answer": "Floating-point numbers",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Boolean",
                "Integers",
                "Scientific notation"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which numeral system uses only two digits, 0 and 1?",
            "correct_answer": "Binary",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Octal",
                "Decimal",
                "Hexadecimal"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which numeral system uses eight digits, 0-7?",
            "correct_answer": "Octal",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Binary",
                "Decimal",
                "Hexadecimal"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which numeral system uses ten digits, 0-9?",
            "correct_answer": "Decimal",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Binary",
                "Octal",
                "Hexadecimal"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which numeral system uses sixteen digits, 0-9 and A-F?",
            "correct_answer": "Hexadecimal",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Binary",
                "Octal",
                "Decimal"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which element in Python is used to store values that can be accessed and manipulated in the code?",
            "correct_answer": "Variables",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Numeric operators",
                "String operators",
                "Assignment operators",
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which conventions are commonly followed for naming variables in Python?",
            "correct_answer": "Naming conventions",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Numeric operators",
                "String operators",
                "Assignment operators",
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which element in Python is used to implement recommendations for code formatting and style?",
            "correct_answer": "Implementing PEP-8 recommendations",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Numeric operators",
                "String operators",
                "Assignment operators",
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which type of operators are used to perform mathematical calculations in Python?",
            "correct_answer": "Numeric operators",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "String operators",
                "Assignment operators",
                "Unary operators",
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which type of operators are used to concatenate or repeat strings in Python?",
            "correct_answer": "String operators",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Numeric operators",
                "Assignment operators",
                "Unary operators",
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which type of operators are used to assign values or perform calculations with previously assigned values in Python?",
            "correct_answer": "Assignment operators",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Numeric operators",
                "String operators",
                "Unary operators",
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which type of operators require only one operand in Python?",
            "correct_answer": "Unary operators",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Numeric operators",
                "String operators",
                "Assignment operators",
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which type of operators require two operands in Python?",
            "correct_answer": "Binary operators",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Numeric operators",
                "String operators",
                "Assignment operators",
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which term refers to the rules that determine the order of execution of operators in an expression?",
            "correct_answer": "Priorities and binding",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Numeric operators",
                "String operators",
                "Assignment operators",
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which type of operators are used to perform bitwise operations on binary numbers in Python?",
            "correct_answer": "Bitwise operators",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Numeric operators",
                "String operators",
                "Assignment operators",
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which bitwise operator in Python flips the bits of a number?",
            "correct_answer": "Tilde ()",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Ampersand (&)",
                "Caret (^)",
                "Pipe (|)"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which bitwise operator in Python performs bitwise AND operation on two numbers?",
            "correct_answer": "Ampersand (&)",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Tilde ()",
                "Caret (^)",
                "Pipe (|)"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which bitwise operator in Python performs bitwise XOR (exclusive OR) operation on two numbers?",
            "correct_answer": "Caret (^)",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Tilde ()",
                "Ampersand (&)",
                "Pipe (|)"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which bitwise operator in Python performs bitwise OR operation on two numbers?",
            "correct_answer": "Pipe (|)",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Tilde ()",
                "Ampersand (&)",
                "Caret (^)"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which bitwise operator in Python shifts the bits of a number to the left?",
            "correct_answer": "Double less-than (<<)",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Double greater-than (>>)",
                "Tilde ()",
                "Ampersand (&)",
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which bitwise operator in Python shifts the bits of a number to the right?",
            "correct_answer": "Double greater-than (>>)",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Double less-than (<<)",
                "Tilde ()",
                "Ampersand (&)"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which logical operator in Python returns the opposite of the given boolean value?",
            "correct_answer": "not",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "and",
                "or",
                "xor"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which logical operator in Python returns True if both boolean values are True?",
            "correct_answer": "and",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "not",
                "or",
                "xor"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which logical operator in Python returns True if at least one of the boolean values is True?",
            "correct_answer": "or",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "not",
                "and",
                "xor"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which logical operator in Python returns True if the boolean values are different?",
            "correct_answer": "xor",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "not",
                "and",
                "or"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which operator is used to compare if two values are equal in Python?",
            "correct_answer": "==",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "!=",
                ">",
                ">="
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which operator is used to compare if two values are not equal in Python?",
            "correct_answer": "!=",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "==",
                ">",
                ">="
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which operator is used to compare if the left value is greater than the right value in Python?",
            "correct_answer": ">",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "==",
                "!=",
                ">="
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which operator is used to compare if the left value is greater than or equal to the right value in Python?",
            "correct_answer": ">=",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "==",
                "!=",
                ">"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which operator is used to compare if the left value is less than the right value in Python?",
            "correct_answer": "<",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "==",
                "!=",
                "<="
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which operator is used to compare if the left value is less than or equal to the right value in Python?",
            "correct_answer": "<=",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "==",
                "!=",
                "<"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "What should you be aware of when using floating-point numbers in Python?",
            "correct_answer": "The accuracy of floating-point numbers",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "The precision of floating-point numbers",
                "The scale of floating-point numbers",
                "The range of floating-point numbers",
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which process allows you to convert one data type to another in Python?",
            "correct_answer": "Type casting",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "Type conversion",
                "Type declaration",
                "Type definition",
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which function in Python is used to output data to the console?",
            "correct_answer": "print()",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "input()",
                "sep=",
                "end="
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which function in Python is used to take user input from the console?",
            "correct_answer": "input()",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "print()",
                "sep=",
                "end="
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which keyword parameter in the print() function is used to separate multiple arguments in the output?",
            "correct_answer": "sep=",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "print()",
                "input()",
                "end="
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which keyword parameter in the print() function is used to specify the ending character in the output?",
            "correct_answer": "end=",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "print()",
                "input()",
                "sep="
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which function in Python is used to convert a value to an integer?",
            "correct_answer": "int()",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "float()",
                "str()",
                "bool()"
            ],
        },
        {
            "question": "Which function in Python is used to convert a value to a floating-point number?",
            "correct_answer": "float()",
            "incorrect_answers": [
                "int()",
                "str()",
                "bool()"
            ],
        },
    ]
}